const question = document.querySelector('#question');
const choices = Array.from(document.querySelectorAll('.choice-text'));
const progressText = document.querySelector('#progressText');
const scoreText = document.querySelector('#score');
const progressBarFull = document.querySelector('#progressBarFull');

let currentQuestion = {}
let acceptingAnswers = true
let score = 0
let availableQuestion = []
let availableCounter = 0

const SCORE_POINTS = 10
const MAX_QUESTIONS = 10

function startGame () {
    questionCounter = 0
    score = 0
    availableQuestions = [...questions]
    getNewQuestion()
}

function getNewQuestion (){
    if(availableQuestions.length === 0 || questionCounter > MAX_QUESTIONS) {
        localStorage.setItem('mostRecentScore', score)

        return window.location.assign('/end.html')
    }

    questionCounter++
    progressText.innerText = `Question ${questionCounter} of ${MAX_QUESTIONS}`
    progressBarFull.style.width = `${(questionCounter/MAX_QUESTIONS) * 100}`

    const questionIndex = Math.floor(Math.random() * availableQuestion.length)
    currentQuestion = availableQuestions[questionIndex]
    question.innerText = currentQuestion.question 
}



let questions = [
    {
        question: "in the 2013/2014 season, Steven Gerrardâ€™s famous slip occurred against which team?",
        choice1: 'Chelsea',
        choice2: 'Manchester United',
        choice3: 'Manchester City',
        choice4: 'Arsenal',
        answer: 1,
    },
    {
        question: "Manchester United signed Eric Cantona in 1992 from which team?",
        choice1: 'Blackburn Rovers',
        choice2: 'Newcastle',
        choice3: 'Tottenham',
        choice4: 'Leeds',
        answer: 4,
    },
    {
        question: "Who scored the fastest in hattrick in Premier League History",
        choice1: 'Thierry Henry',
        choice2: 'Sadio Mane',
        choice3: 'Luis Suarez',
        choice4: 'Robbie Fowler',
        answer: 2,
    },
    {
        question: "What did Jose Mourinho refer himself as in his first ever press conference for Chelsea?",
        choice1: 'The happy one',
        choice2: 'The special one',
        choice3: 'The legendary one',
        choice4: 'The chosen one',
        answer: 2,
    },
    {
        question: "How many goals did Manchester city score on their way to winning the premier league title in the 2017/2018 season?",
        choice1: '102',
        choice2: '100',
        choice3: '106',
        choice4: '103',
        answer: 3,
    },
    {
        question: "I have played for Man City, Chelsea, Liverpool, Arsenal, West Brom and Bolton Wanderers - Who am I?",
        choice1: 'James Beattie',
        choice2: 'Peter Crouch',
        choice3: 'Nicolas Anelka',
        choice4: 'Jermaine Defoe',
        answer: 3,
    },
    {
        question: "Which former dutch player was famously nicknamed 'the non-flying Dutchman'?",
        choice1: 'Wesley Sneijder',
        choice2: 'Robin Van Persie',
        choice3: 'Rafael Van Der Vaart',
        choice4: 'Dennis Bergkamp',
        answer: 4,
    },
    {
        question: "Which defeated Arsenal to end their 49 games unbeaten run?",
        choice1: 'Manchester United',
        choice2: 'Liverpool',
        choice3: 'Chelsea',
        choice4: 'Everton',
        answer: 1,
    },
    {
        question: "Alan Sugar was once the chairman and part owner of which team?",
        choice1: 'West Ham',
        choice2: 'Tottenham',
        choice3: 'Crystal Palace',
        choice4: 'Southampton',
        answer: 2,
    },
    {
        question: "Which club is nicknamed 'The Toffees'?",
        choice1: 'Fulham',
        choice2: 'Crystal Palace',
        choice3: 'Newcastle',
        choice4: 'Everton',
        answer: 4,
    },
    {
        question: "Sam Allardyce managed which team between 1999-2007?",
        choice1: 'Watford',
        choice2: 'Southampton',
        choice3: 'Norwich',
        choice4: 'Bolton Wanderers',
        answer: 4,
    },
    {
        question: "Which country did former Blackburn Rovers player Morten Gamst Pedersen represent?",
        choice1: 'Denmark',
        choice2: 'Norway',
        choice3: 'Sweden',
        choice4: 'Finland',
        answer: 2,
    },
    {
        question: "Jurgen Klopp took over as Liverpool coach in which year?",
        choice1: '2015',
        choice2: '2014',
        choice3: '2016',
        choice4: '2017',
        answer: 1,
    },
];


